我刚刚..准备试试万圣节的服装
I was--I was just... trying on my halloween costume.
你到底想扮成什么
What exactly are you supposed to be?
太空牛仔
Space cowboy.
首先  太空没牛仔
Ok. A, there are no cows in space.
其次  五年前你不是穿过这身吗
B, didn't you wear that, like, five years ago?
-所以呢  -不想换件别的穿
- So? - So don't you think you should move on?
就喜欢这身  这么晚你还在做什么
I like it. What are you doing up so late anyway?
万圣节的功课
Halloween homework--
《掠夺者们》 《电锯惊魂》根据这本书改编
"The pit & the pendulum," the original "Saw."
想好今年过节穿什么了吗
Have you decided what you're gonna dress up as this year?
英迪拉·甘地  阿梅莉亚·埃尔哈特
Perhaps Indira Gandhi, Amelia Earhart?
赫敏
Oh! Hermione?
我不想过万圣节了
I think I'm gonna skip it.
不过节啦
Skip Halloween?
打扮好  不就是照样站在门口发糖
Well, dressing up. I'll still hand out candy at the door,
我已经过了玩不给糖就捣乱的年纪了
but I'm too old to go trick-or-treating anymore.
知道看到那些孩子来  我什么感觉吗
And you know how I feel when the big kids come.
我可不想当那种孩子
I don't want to be that kid.
但你得和我一起去
But you have to go with me.
你是我的糖胡子
You are my candy beard.
对不起爸爸  你得另找个糖胡子了
Sorry, dad. You're just gonna have to get another beard.
这件事我们每年都争
This discussion is not over.
你们在那个父母培训组
So... have you come up with a name
为这个蛋宝宝起好名字了吗
for your parenting project baby egg yet?
等等  我先猜猜
Wait. Let--let me guess.
扎克·弗隆宝宝  还是小艾德·博格里宝宝
Zac Eggfron? No. Egg Begley JR.?
我起了个狄更斯式的名字  佩吉和我叫他费吉恩
I went dickensian. Paige and I are calling him Feggin.
-能明白吧  -费吉恩
- Get it? - Feggin?
-假的蛋宝宝[费吉恩的谐音]  -假蛋蛋如何
- Fake baby egg. - Wouldn't that be fakegg?
贝克特  这么晚有何贵干
Beckett, what are you doing up so late?
我很喜欢一年中的这个时节
Ah, I just love this time of year--
脚下清脆作响的落叶  清新爽洁的空气
Crunchy leaves underfoot, the crisp, clean air,
点着南瓜灯的味道
The smell of jack-o'-lanterns all aflame.
警察说不出这种话
Yeah, well, you wouldn't say that if you were a cop.
万圣节算是我们一年里最难熬的日子
Halloween's one of the worst weeks of the year for us.
尸体进了墓地
The body's already in a graveyard.
有的人想省点时间
Someone was trying to save some time.
我喜欢在墓地里走
I do love walking through cemeteries.
喜欢看他们的故事  看这个
I love their stories. Check out this one.
伊里莎白·戴登  1962年12月3日至...
"Elizabeth Dryden, December 3, 1962-?"
连死亡日期都不清楚  这里埋的又是什么呢
If they don't even know when she die, what's buried here?
你穿着吊裤带吗
Are you wearing suspenders?
试试万圣节晚会的礼服
I'm trying on costumes for my annual halloween party.
礼服可不能少
Costumes are mandatory.
-什么情况  -看看吧
- What's the story, you guys? - Take a look.
不会吧  他心脏上插的是木钉吗
Are you kidding me? Is that a stake in his heart?
看来吸血鬼猎人巴菲光顾纽约了
Looks like Buffy's visited the big apple.
-有人把他当成吸血鬼了  -看着也像
- Someone thought he was a vampire. - So did he.
这可不像塑料制品
And they're not plastic pop-ins either.
你是说这是真牙吗
Are you telling me those are real?
-可能是高档烤瓷牙  -或者此人就是吸血鬼
- Or high-end veneers. - Or he's a vampire.
没身份证  没电话
No I.D. No phone.
附近都找遍了
We got guys sweepin' the area for anything they can find.
-也没有目击证人  -看起来像扭打过
- No witnesses either. - Looks like he struggled.
他的头撞到这块石头
I'm thinking he hit his head on this stone
或是被人揪住头撞向石头  然后又捅了一下
or someone knocked him in the head before he was stabbed.
谁会费这么大劲杀人
Who would go to the trouble of killing someone that way?
狼人  他们和吸血鬼不共戴天
Lycans. They've been at war with the vampires
宿怨从15世纪卢西恩被杀就结下了
Ever since Lucian was murdered in the 15th century...
当然这只是个人想法
Again, this is just theory.
哪里不对
What is wrong?
如果他是吸血鬼  拔出木钉
If he's a vampire and you pull that out,
就会起死回生
He comes back to life.
能活过来  我们就可以早点回家
If he does, then we can all go home early.
搞清他是什么人或什么物吗
Any idea as to who or... what he is?
他是人类  獠牙是烤瓷的
He's human, and the fangs are ceramic veneers.
大腿动脉有两处新撕痕
But he has two fresh avulsions near the femoral artery.
大腿上的是咬痕吗
Bite marks on his thigh?
我在尸体上找到这个
And I found these on his body.
人造纤维  杀手戴着假发
They're synthetic. Your killer was wearing a wig.
把木钉插进心脏可非易事
It can't be easy to drive a stake through someone's chest.
打碎胸腔  还得用上石头
To break the rib cage, you'd have to pound it in with a rock.
某人行刺前看来忘记洗手了
Someone didn't wash their hands before the stabbing.
看看这些黑色污迹
Check out these black smudges.
让犯罪现场组查查这根木钉
You know, have C.S.U. run the stake.
找到与死者吻合的指纹了吗
Any match on the vic's prints?
系统里没有  失踪人口里也没有
Nothing in the system, no hits with missing persons,
查不出身份
No I.D.
-但他的牙能以假乱真  -所以呢
- But he has professional veneers. - Yeah. So?
我认识城里最棒的獠牙制造大师
I know the best fangmaster in the city.
-也许他能认出死者  -獠牙制造大师
- Maybe he could identify him. - Fangmaster?
卡塞尔  希望你说的是真的
I hope this is for real, Castle,
否则  我们就有愚弄无名尸的嫌疑
Because if it's not, we're shortchanging our John Doe.
相信我  真不敢相信你们居然没听说这地方
Oh, trust me. I can't believe you've never heard this place.
我的全套行头都在这里买的
I get all my costumes here.
正好给你选一套装扮来参加我的万圣节派队
We can use this opportunity to find you one for my halloween party.
思春的小护士如何
How about... slutty nurse?
卡塞尔  你这是痴心妄想
Fantasize all you want, Castle.
我怎么可能为了你穿那些
I am not trying on costumes for you.
不穿  为什么不  你有行头了
No? Why not? You already got one
谁说我要参加你的派对
Who says I'm even coming to your party?
理查德·卡塞尔  改主意了
Richard Castle. Change your mind?
我给你来一副双层加固  肯定适合你
I'd love to fit you with a nice set of doubles.
医生  今天来是为了公事
Uh, official police business today, doc.
贝克特警探  介绍一下
Detective Beckett, I would like to
牙科天才巴瑞·弗兰克
Introduce you to Dr. Barry Frank-- dental genius
顶尖的獠牙制造大师
And fangmaster extraordinaire.
布拉德·皮特《夜访吸血鬼》的假牙
He did, Brad Pitt's veneers for
也是出自他手
"Interview with the vampire."
我能帮你什么忙吗  大师就在这里
So what can I do for you? The master is in.
我们正在调查一起凶杀案
We're investigating a homicide,
死者做过牙
And our victim had some work done.
希望你能帮忙辨认一下此人
We were hoping you could help identify him.
那人叫克鲁
Oh. That's Crow.
我给他镶过牙  好像是两个月前吧
I did his veneers about, uh, I don't know, two months ago.
克鲁
Crow?
崇拜吸血鬼的人
Oh, people in the vampire fetish community,
不用俗家的名字
They give up their mundane names.
没人会用大卫  查克或梅杰这种名字
You're not gonna find any Daves or Chucks or Megs here.
他人不错  出什么事了
He seemed like a nice kid. What happened?
我们会查明的
That's what we're trying to figure out.
希望你能提供他的本名或账单地址
We were hoping you would have a legal name or a billing address.
-好  我去找  -谢谢
- Sure. Just, uh, let me look it up. - Thank you.
卡塞尔  你在做什么
Castle, what are you doing?
这能带给我不死之躯吗
Do these make me look immortal?
想让我来咬一口吗
Do you want to, uh, go get something pierced?
不  你呢
No. Do you?
这是马修的公寓
This is Matthew's apartment.
你们觉得他很捣蛋  但马修却是安静害羞
You'd think he'd be trouble,but Matthew was a quiet kid, shy
最近有没有听到或看到异常的事
Had, you, uh, heard or seen anything unusual lately?
扮吸血鬼有些怪异
The vampire thing was a little weird,
但我第一任丈夫是内战重演爱好者
But my first husband was a civil war reenactor.
你们说哪个更怪呢
So you tell me, which is weirder?
-简直是艺术家  -对  不过大多是漫画
- Ah, he was quite the artist.- Yeah, but mostly comic books.
让我想到早期的弗兰克·米勒
It reminds me of early Frank Miller.
哪部 史诗系列《300》还是《黑骑士归来》
Which Frank--epic 300 or dark horse years?
天啊  这是你说过最吸引人的话
Oh, my god. That is the sexiest thing I ever heard you say.
没料到你还喜欢漫画书
I had no idea you were interested in comic books.
卡塞尔  我的事你不了解的多着呢
Oh, Castle. The things you don't know about me could fill a book.
看这个
Hey. Check this out.
他在制作漫画书
He was developing a graphic novel.
很有才华
He's talented.
克鲁谈起过自己的家人吗
Did Crow ever talk about his family?
从来没有
Well, he never mentioned any.
我想这孩子要自立  不太合群
I just figured he was pretty much on his own, a loner.
他像在巴克尔设计学院上学
It looks like he went to the Barker school of design.
虽然与现实社会联系不多
There's only a partial social.
但通过学校应该能找到
But we should be able to track down
孩子的亲人
His next of kin through the school.
有朋友或什么人来公寓找过他吗
He ever have any friends or visitors to his apartment?
有个女孩  他带回来过一两次
He brought a girl here once or twice.
她也是吸血鬼团体的
She was one of them.
笑的时候露出那种牙
You could see them when she smiled.
有一晚他们大吵一架
They did have a big fight the other night.
女孩不停地叫嚷
She was screaming bloody murder.
她长什么样
What did she look like?
一头黑发  搭在獠牙上
Uh, she had long black hair, to her tush--
-黑色长发  -对
- Long black hair? - Yeah.
-知道名字吗  -不清楚
- Did you get a name? - No.
他说过  那姑娘有些名气
He told me that she was famous or something.
她有自己的网站
Uh, he said she had her own web site on the Internet.
我们可以查查他的浏览记录
Well, we could check his browser history.
你觉得那是真的吗  那些獠牙
You think they're real? uh, the fangs, I mean.
吸血鬼情妇威妮森
Vampire mistress Vixen.
她的俱乐部取名为藏污纳垢
Her coven is called the den of iniquity.
俱乐部
Coven?
吸血鬼俱乐部  类似教会或俱乐部
Yeah, a vampire coven is like joining a church or a club.
你喜欢打高尔夫球  我喜欢打高尔夫球
You like to play golf. I like to play golf.
你喜欢吸血  我喜欢吸血
You like to drink blood. I like to drink blood.
我曾经和一个过吸血鬼生活的女孩约会
I used to go out with a girl who was into the lifestyle.
后来怎么了  关系搞砸啦
What happened? Did the relationship suck?
血色交易  她想在棺材里做爱
The deal breaker? She wanted to have sex in a coffin.
我这个人很开放  但开放的方面不同
I'm open-minded. I'm not that open-minded.
有没有这位
All right. Did our mistress of the night
黑暗小姐的电话或地址
Have a phone number or an address?
只有一封电邮
Uh, only an e-mail.
里面有下次集会的消息
However, there is information on the coven's next gathering,
就在今晚
Which meets tonight.
-见鬼  需要密码  -或把前女友找来
- Damn. You need a password. - Or an old girlfriend.
大概有一年没见过她了
Hey. Whoa. I haven't seen her in, like, a year.
好  但我不和她上床
Fine, but I am not sleeping with her.
我在找威妮森
I'm looking for Vixen.
劳驾  借过
Coming by. Pardon me. Excuse me.
《灵书妙探》第二季
第六集  沉迷
你们是吸血者吗
You're, uh, sanguinarians? Blood drinkers.
我们的活动都是合法的自愿的
All of our blood play is legal and consensual.
我们不是为了俱乐部的事来的
We're not here about the club.
认识马修·弗雷曼吗
Do you know somebody named Matthew Freeman?
-谁  -克鲁
- Who? - Crow.
克鲁  当然  怎么  他有麻烦了
Crow? Sure. Why? Is he in some kind of trouble?
我们在墓地发现他
We found him in a cemetery.
被人用木钉插进心脏
Someone put a stake through his heart.
那是开玩笑吗
What is this, some kind of joke?
开吸血鬼的玩笑吗
Let's go make fun of the vampires?
-不是玩笑  -不可能  出什么事了
- It's not a joke. - No way. What?
谁会用那种方式杀死克鲁
Who would want to kill Crow like that?
本指望问你们呢
We were hoping you could tell us
昨晚11点到12点间你在哪里
Where were you last night between 11:00 p.m.and midnight?
这里  等等  你们不会说人是我杀的吧
I was here. W-wait. You don't think I'm responsible?
我们在他身上发现一些黑色假发
We found synthetic hairs on his body from a black wig
大腿上还有咬痕
And bites on his thigh.
我没杀他  他是我的情人之一
But I didn't kill him. He was one of my lovers.
昨天见到他了吗
So you saw him yesterday?
中午吧  他下午3:30走的  真可怕
Mid afternoon he left. 3:30. Oh, my god. It's so awful.
-威妮森  -他真死了
- Vixen. - He's really dead?
有人看到你们最近起过争执
We have a witness who told us that you were fighting recently.
因为他和别人约会
Yeah, because he'd been seeing someone else.
我们最终原谅他了  昨天我们做爱了
Ultimately, we forgave him. Yesterday, we were... making up.
所以你们在他身上发现我的头发
That's why you found my hair on him.
-你说他和别人约会  -戴蒙
- You said he was seeing someone else. - Daemon.
戴蒙喜欢上克鲁的作品
Daemon fell in love with Crow and his art
还跟他谈出漫画书的事
And talked him into writing a graphic novel.
这是他的死因
That's why he's dead.
那本漫画名字叫《永恒之血》
Their graphic novel, "Blood everlasting,"
讲得是纽约城一个吸血鬼的故事
Is about a vampire in New York city.
故事根据真实事件改编  很可怕
Only the guide they were based on was real and dangerous.
真的吸血鬼
A real vampire?
那人认为自己就是吸血鬼  摩根·洛克白
He thinks he is. His name's Morgan Lockerby.
这个俱乐部的创始人之一
He was an original member of this coven,
但后来他出了点事
But something happened to him.
他脱离了现实
He lost all hold of reality.
开始相信吸血鬼真实存在
He started believing that this was real.
他现在只在晚上出来  到墓地游荡
N-now he only comes out at night and hangs out at the cemetery.
这太疯狂了
It was just crazy.
怎么找到这个洛克白
How do we find this Lockerby?
他无家可归  但戴蒙或许知道
He's homeless, but Daemon probably knows.
戴蒙有姓氏吗
Daemon have a last name?
我不知道他的真名
I don't know his real name.
他是克劳的男友  不是我的
He was Crow's boyfriend, not mine.
这些人怎么想的
You know, what is it with these people
打扮成吸血鬼
And their dressing up like vampires--
成立俱乐部  还演戏
The covens, the--the drama?
这与服饰和装扮无关
Well, it's not about the costumes or the makeup.
许多沉迷于幻想的人
A lot of the people who are committed to the fantasy
有些怪异
Are a little different.
他们只是想找个能融入的圈子
They're just looking for a place to fit in.
好  明白了
Okay, that I get.
表现就是  沉迷于对死亡的话题
It's just this whole fascination with the macabre--
不光自己喝血  还与人共饮
The drinking of the blood, the sharing of the blood,
在棺材里做爱
The, uh, having sex in coffins.
《心理学101原理》指出
Psychology 101
这些人很可能在小时候
They probably had something happen to them
经历过一些事情
When they were younger.
目睹过自家的狗被车撞死
Maybe they saw their dog get hit by a car,
参加过有灵柩的葬礼
Attended an on-casket funeral,
痛失幼年的玩伴
Had a loss of a childhood friend
或  失去父母
Or... Parent.
有人当了吸血鬼  有人做了警察
Some people become vampires. Some people become cops.
好吧  那你对死亡主题的迷恋
Okay. Then where did your fascination
是因何而来
With the macabre come from?
你身上发生过什么
What happened to you?
那个艺校注册信息
Yo. That art school registration info?
已获准从巴克学校提取马修·弗雷曼的信息
Court order from Barker came through for Matthew Freeman,
又名克劳
A.K.A. Crow.
家住康涅狄格州  电话号码在上面
His family's in Connecticut. Phone number's there.
俱乐部那边进展如何
How'd it go at the club?
摸摸摩根·洛克白的底细  看看有什么发现
Um, Morgan Lockerby. Run him and see what you can find.
再查查克劳的朋友  戴蒙
And see if you can find Crow's friend Daemon.
他有姓氏吗
Does he have a last name?
我都不清楚  这个名字是不是真的
I'm not even sure that's his real first name.
怎么  身为警探  调查是天职
What? You guys are detectives. Detect.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
-你还好吗  -我讨厌干这个
- Are you okay? - I-I hate this part.
一通电话  掉转乾坤
It's the, uh, phone call that changes everything.
-需要的话  我留下  -不了  谢谢
- I could stay if you like. - Oh, no. Thank you.
有时自己处理更好
Sometimes it's easier without an audience.
弗雷曼先生和弗雷曼夫人
Mr. And Mrs. Freeman,
你们认为谁会害你儿子呢
Do you have any idea who would try to harm your son?
不知道  马修对自己的生活绝口不提
No. Matthew was very private about his life.
他那些所谓的朋友我们所知甚少
There was little we knew about his so-called friends.
-妈  -我知道那些人很危险
- Mom. - I knew those people were dangerous.
-我该阻止他陷入其中  -艾伦
- I shoulda stopped him from getting involved. - Alan.
他在巴克设计学校注册过
He was registered at the Barker school of design.
-他去上过学吗  -没有  他辍学了
- Did he ever attend? - No. He--he dropped out.
最后一次见马修是什么时候
And when was the last time you saw Matthew?
好几个月没见到马修了
It's been months since we've seen Matthew.
不对  现在该叫克劳
No, it was Crow now.
他回过家  一身黑
He came home. He was dressed in black.
胳膊上纹着骷髅头
He had skulls tattooed on his arm...
画着眼线  带着獠牙
Eyeliner on his eyes, fangs.
我真该多多管教他
I shoulda gotten tougher on him.
看  他只是个普通的小男孩
See? He was just a... a normal little boy.
后来沉迷于艺术
And then he fell in love with art.
变得喜怒无常  然后
Then he got moody and--and...
他开始和这些人打交道
He started hanging out with those people.
他最后一通电话是在什么时候
When did you hear from him last?
几天前来过电话  留了言
He called a couple of days ago and he left a message.
好像很伤心
And he sounded upset.
我们再也问不出原因了
But we never found out why.
-棘手吗  -对  很棘手
- Tough one? - Yeah. They're all tough.
有发现吗
So you got anything?
对  威妮森的不在场证明核实了
Yeah, Vixen's alibi checked out.
我们同克劳的吸血鬼朋友谈过
We've been talking to Crow's coven friends
还在吸血鬼网站搜索过
And searching through vampire web sites.
还是查不出戴蒙
So far, no Daemon.
洛克白呢
What about lockerby?
摩根·洛克白  精神失常
Morgan Lockerby-- Psychiatric disorder,
35岁  全国通缉
35, committed by the state.
这是好消息
That's the good news.
坏消息是  几年前他逃跑了
Bad news is, he escaped a few years back.
此后没人见过他
Nobody's seen him since.
-记录上有住址吗  -没有  居无定所
- Got an address on file? - No. He's completely off grid.
你的跟班在干什么
What's your shadow doing?
不知道  上次我见到他
I don't know. Last time I saw him,
他在克劳的公寓里面搜查证据
He was sifting through evidence from Crow's apartment.
-你打算去吗  -什么
- So are you going? - To what?
他的万圣节派对
His Halloween party.
没想好  他办的派对太多了  你呢
I don't know. He throws a lot of parties. You?
别逗我  我爱死派对
Are you kidding? I'm all over that.
-你要穿什么去  -想知道吗
- What are you gonna wear? - You want to know?
那你就得去  看看我到底穿什么
You gotta show... To see what I got going on.
卡塞尔  忙这个案子呢
Hot on the case, Castle?
在读一些好东西
On the case of a good read. It's actually not bad.
埃斯波西托发现了摩根·洛克白
Esposito found Morgan Lockerby.
你是说摩洛克
You mean... Morlock.
威妮森说的对
Vixen was right.
你身上有樱桃味
You smell like cherries.
我们发现了
Hey, we got a hit on the...
我们是不是来的不是时候
Are we interrupting something?
-对  -没有
- Yes. - No.
好的
Okay.
你们有何发现
Wh-what'd you get a hit on?
插进克劳心脏的木钉上的污迹
The, uh, prints from the stake in Crow's heart.
-女孩威妮森说得对  -指纹属于摩根·洛克白
- Your girl Vixen was right. - Morgan Lockerby.
只可惜  此人无处可找
Only thing is, he's one of the great unfindables.
没地址  没电话  没有踪迹
No address, no phone number, no trail.
也许有呢  看这
Maybe not. Here.
认出这个拐角了吗
Recognize that corner?
布鲁姆和克林顿  在纽约下东区
That's Broome and Clinton, lower east side.
克劳可能给我们画了张地图去找摩洛克
I think Crow may have drawn us a road map to Morlock.
这里走
It's that way.
不会吧
You gotta be kidding me.
-他就睡这里面  -现在是白天
- You think he's in there? - It is daytime.
如果他认为自己是吸血鬼  就会躺这里面
If he thinks he's a vampire, that's where he'd be.
有我呢
I'll cover you.
-一起来吧  -好  数三下
- Together? - All right. On three.
好
Okay.
-一  -一
- One... - One...
-二  -二
- Two... - Two...
-三  -三
- Three. - Three.
见他蹿出来了吗
You see him jump?
真是男子汉  卡塞尔
Real macho, Castle.
把他弄开  把他弄开
Get him off! Get him off!
-把他从我身上弄开  -从他身上弄开
- Get him off me! - Get him off of him.
-他咬我  -真是个吸血鬼
- Aah! He bit me. - Look! He is a vampire.
他不是吸血鬼
He's not a vampire.
但阳光把他灼伤了
But his skin burned when the light hit him.
他有卟啉症  也称吸血鬼病
He has porphyria. Some people call it the vampire disease.
症状之一就是对光极度敏感
Its symptoms include extreme photosensitivity.
若暴露在阳光下  皮肤就会起泡
The skin blisters when it's exposed to the sun.
患者容易产生幻觉和妄想
Victims are prone to hallucinations, paranoia.
这也说明了他的精神诊断
That explains his psych diagnosis.
这病传染吗
Exactly how contagious is it?
这是遗传病
It's a genetic disease.
另外  我在咬伤处涂了抗生素
Besides, I put enough antibiotics on that bite
以杀死细菌
To kill the small animal.
如果没事了  我要回去
Now if we're done here, I gotta head back to the slab
看一具男尸
And see a man about a corpse.
谢谢  帕里什医生  卡塞尔可被吓坏了
Thank you, Dr. Parish. Castle was totally freaked out.
想咬我  就得请客
You want to bite me? You buy me dinner.
洛克白先生
Mr. Lockerby.
摩洛克  认不认识克劳
Morlock, do you know somebody named Crow?
狠毒的贱人  到处都是斑点
Heartless bitch! Spots all over.
全是斑点
S-spots all over.
你当时和克劳在墓地吗
Were you in the cemetery with Crow?
到处都是血  到处是血
Blood all over! Blood all over.
杀手在场  洛克白先生
There's been a murder, Mr. Lockerby.
你明白吗
Do you understand that?
你有没有和克劳去墓地
Were you in the cemetery with Crow?
木钉上全是你的指纹
We found a wooden stake with your fingerprints all over it.
那只猫爬进来把鸟杀了
Ah! The cat creeps in to kill the bird.
我该把你藏起来  可怜的孩子
I should've buried you then, wicked boy.
当时我该把你藏起来
I should've buried you then.
我没看见  看不到  看不到  看不到
Can--I didn't see. I didn't see. I didn't see.
真不想教公共辩护人该怎么做
I don't want to tell the public defender how to do her job,
但我想说  精神病的证词可能有价值
But I'm gonna say that the insanity plea might be appropriate.
或许找个精神病医生  可以在他被带走之前
Maybe the state psychiatrist can help us make sense
帮我们弄懂摩洛克的疯话
Out of Morlock's rantings before they take him away.
好  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
实验室打来的  他们告诉我
That was the lab. They were calling me to tell me
木钉上的墨点是印度墨水
That the smudge on the stake was India ink.
摩洛克经过垃圾桶时沾到的
Morlock must have gotten some on his hands Going through a dumpster.
-印度墨水  -对  怎么了
- India ink? - Yeah. Why?
印度还是中国墨水
India ink, or Chinese ink,
从公元前4000开始就使用墨水
Has been used since 4th century B.C. when we've got nothing.
它与水不互溶
It's water resistent.
所以上完色后不会弄脏
So it won't smudge when colored over.
漫画书对白的设计者使用墨水
It's also the ink used by letterers in comic books.
所以如果克劳画插画
So if Crow was the illustrator...
那么  他的朋友戴蒙写对白
Then Crow's friend Daemon was the letterer.
-可墨水怎么跑到木钉上  -这是问题所在
- But what would the ink be doing on the stake? - What indeed.
你们查出他那位朋友没有
You guys, where are we on the friend?
还在查
We're working on it.
是吗  加快速度好吗
Yeah? Well, could you work a little faster?
-卡塞尔  帮个忙好吗  -乐意效劳
- Hey, castle, you wanna help? - I would love to,
可我还要雕刻大南瓜
But I have got bigger pumpkins to carve.
万圣节前夕  在卡塞尔家大厅
It was Halloween night, at the Castle hall
所有人都在雕南瓜怪杰
And everybody came to the monster's ball
你的吸血鬼查的怎么样了
How's your nosferatu coming?
做好空心南瓜灯的关键
The key to a good jack-o'-lantern
就是掌握好反面的效果
Is understanding negative space.
不在于有什么  而在于没有什么
It's not what's there. It's what's not there.
小蝗虫  我已经教会你了
Ah, I have taught you well, grasshopper.
今天两个南瓜雕刻大师
Oh. What are my two pumpkin masters carving
为派对刻出了什么了
For this year's party?
我在做传统的南瓜灯
I am carving the traditional jack-o'-lantern--
南瓜怪杰先生的脸
Mr. Scary pumpkin face.
我在雕刻麦克斯·希瑞克扮演的角色  欧洛克
And I am carving max Schreck in his role as Count Orlok.
爸爸是个小吸血鬼迷  因为他的案子
Dad's a little vampire obsessed because of his case.
也可能是因为被咬了一口
Or maybe it's because of the bite.
我敢发誓  你没有灵感了
I swear, you have missed your calling.
我都不知道你为什么还要写
I don't even know why you bother to write.
要一起来吗
Hey, you want to carve with us?
不行  我要去化装舞会
Oh, can't. I'm off to a masquerade ball.
-或许会遇到我的盖兹比 -妈妈  我有印象
- Perhaps I'll meet my Gatsby. - Oh! Mother, I'm impressed.
-你穿舞会装还那么合适  -谢谢  亲爱的
- You still fit into your prom dress. - Oh, thank you, darling.
-你问过他了吗  -我在等合适的时机
- Have you asked him yet? - I was waiting for the right moment.
问我什么
Asked me what?
佩吉和我收到万圣节前夕舞会的邀请
Paige and I got invited to a party tomorrow--
邀请我们的是高年级同学
The night before halloween-- By seniors.
你奶奶的同学吗
By your grandmother's friends?
不是  爸爸  十二年级的学生
No, dad. Twelfth graders.
不过  有老师在
But it'll be supervised.
这是人生的十字路口  是吧
This is one of those crossroads moments, isn't it?
由她去吧
Oh, let her go.
她可比你那会儿懂事多了
She's far more responsible than you ever were.
好  你去吧
Yes, you can go.
但如果有任何不快
But if anything happens that makes you feel uncomfortable,
不管是什么事  打电话给我  无论发生什么
Anything at all, you call me. I don't care what it is.
我保证不罚你  也不指责你
And there'll be no punishments, no recriminations,
我保证  记得打电话就好
Nothing, I promise, just so long as you call.
好  我会的  但不会出事的
Okay. Yeah, yeah, I will, I promise. But nothing's gonna happen.
-还有一件事  -什么
-But there's one more thing, though.- Yes.
-能帮我照看费吉恩吗  -怎么  要孵小鸡了
-Will you watch Feggin?  -Why, is he gonna hatch?
不是  我们健康课的老师说  不能让它单独呆着
No. Our health teacher says we can't leave him alone.
不然就是虐待蛋蛋
That's considered egg abuse.
我和佩吉要共同抚养
And since Paige and I are co-parenting,
可是  我们都要去参加派对
And we're both going to the party
她父母也要出门  就得找个保姆
And her parents are going out, we need a sitter.
不好意思  我没空
Oh, no. sorry. Uh, plans.
好  没问题  我会看着你的鸡蛋宝宝的
Yeah, okay. Sure. I'll watch your little egg child.
但你得知道  做爷爷  我还太年轻了点
But I want you to know, I'm far too young to be a grandparent.
还有  如果有高年级男生骚扰你...
And if, uh, any of those senior boys bother you...
老爸我是绝不会姑息的
Father won't be quite himself.
他一直喃喃自语  大吼大叫  往栏杆上撞
He mumbles, He shouts, he throws himself against the bars,
不过也就如此而已
But the's just something about it.
尽管像洛克白先生这样的人
Although someone like Mr. Lockerby
会表现得完全精神失常...
Will present as completely non compos mentis.
还是有清醒的时候
He could still have moments of lucidity.
问题就在于  如何区分幻觉与现实
The difficulty is separating the fantasy from the reality.
这些都是受害者画的
Well, these were drawn by our victim.
我在想  这是不是在揭示着
I was wondering if they suggested anything
他跟洛克白先生的关系
About his relationship with Mr. Lockerby.
我得继续研究下  才能得出诊断结果
I'd have to study them more to give you a diagnosis,
不过这跟那女的关系更大点
But these are more about the woman in the drawings
-而不是洛克白先生  -什么意思
-Than Lockerby.  - What do you mean?
他把她描绘成天使
He draws her as an angel,
但却总以暴力作为背景
But always in the context of an act of violence.
老实说  这更像是一个
Honestly? It looks to me like the work of someone
受过精神创伤的人的作品
Who was once traumatized.
童年创伤  我说过的吧
Childhood trauma. What'd I tell you?
霍洛威医生 这位是理查德·卡塞尔
Doc Holloway, this is Richard Castle.
霍洛威医生  费吉恩快向这位心理专家问好
Dr. Holloway. Say hello to the nice psychiatrist, Feggin.
你好
Hello.
我会安排
I will arrange for someone
社会服务处的义工来接洛克白先生
From social services to come get Mr. Lockerby.
你愿意的话  我也可以派人来接他
And if you want, I can have someone get him, too.
好的  谢谢
Yes, please.
你打算吃了它吗
Are you gonna eat that?
吃我的孙子  你当我是谁  大怪兽
Eat my own grandchild? What am I, a monster?
也许被咬了以后之后  你还真携带了啥病毒
Maybe that bite was catching.
这是学校的自然科学课
It's a school health sciences project--
在你学会承担责任之前
Helping de-romanticize having a family
先以浪漫化手法  组织一个家庭
Before you're ready to take responsibility.
阿丽克西斯和佩吉今晚初次参加高年级派对
Alexis and Paige are going to their first senior party tonight,
我就成了保姆  照顾鸡蛋宝宝
So I'm babysitting. Egg-sitting.
-高年级派对  -怎么了
-Senior party, huh? -What?
-贝克特  -我们给邻居们看了克鲁的照片
- Beckett.  - We showed Crow's picture around the neighborhood.
找到了他朋友戴蒙的线索
We got a lead on his friend Daemon.
说出来你都不会信  这家伙死了
You're not gonna believe this. The guy is dead.
一枪直接命中心脏而亡
Shot right through the heart,
住处也被人翻过了
And his place has been tossed.
另外说一下...
Oh... and, uh...
他是个狼人
He's a werewolf.
-被银弹打死的  -不  9毫米子弹
- Silver bullet?   - No, 9 millimeter.
-那我猜他不是真正的狼人  -对
- Then I guess he's not a real werewolf.  - Nice.
他脸上手上的毛发  都是人造的
The hairs on his face and hands are synthetic,
用化妆胶水粘上去的  万圣节装扮
Attached with spirit gum. It's a halloween costume.
从他的驾照来看
According to his driver's license,
戴蒙真名叫乔纳斯·维斯特福尔
Daemon's real name was Jonas Westfall.
毕业于纽约大学  法医人类学专业
He's a graduate student N.Y.U. In forensic anthropology.
所以会有这么多骨头
Then that explains the bones.
-卡塞尔  别碰  -我知道
- Castle, don't touch.  - I know.
我们细查了这栋楼
Canvassed the building.
邻居们那天听些动静
Neighbor remembers hearing something the other day
-万圣节那天还有车来过  -那天
- But there was a car back in Hallowmas - Tht other day?
根据尸体的腐化和瘀青程度
Based on deterioration and lividity
还有那泰国菜的馊味
And the smell of that old Thai food,
这狼人跟咱们那吸血鬼  是同一天被杀的
Wolf boy was killed the same day as our vampire.
可以说  比他还早几小时
I'd say a couple of hours before.
莱恩  查查送外卖的人
Ryan, track down the delivery guy.
查查外卖送达的时间
Find out when this was delivered
还有  当时有没有别人在场
And whether anyone else was up here when he brought it.
以另外个自己  过来参加
"Come as your alter ego"?
10月27日晚7点  他本打算参加这个派对
"October 27th at 7:00 p.m." our guy was going to this party.
即克鲁被害的同一天
Same day that Crow was killed.
我认为二者有关连
I assume there's a connection.
印度墨水
India ink,
也就是说  杀克鲁的凶手也来过这
Which means Crow's killer was in the apartment, too.
但他们到底在找什么呢
But what were they looking for?
卡塞尔
Castle.
莫洛克
Morlock?
他来这  打杀了戴蒙  拿走木钉
He comes here, shoots Daemon, grabs a stake
又去害克鲁
Goes off and kills Crow.
扭打中打碎了墨水瓶
And in the struggle, the ink bottle is broken.
不会是莫洛克  这名受害者是白天被杀的
Wasn't Morlock. This victim was killed during the day.
莫洛克有卟啉症  他不能见阳光的
Morlock had porphyria. He would've burnt to a crisp.
如果这狼人不是他杀的
So if he didn't kill our werewolf...
也有可能  吸血鬼也不是他杀的
Then chances are he didn't kill our vempire.
那木钉上怎么会有他的指纹
Well, then how did the prints get on the stake?
也许  他是想帮忙
Maybe he was trying to help him.
也许就是想救朋友
Maybe he was trying to save his friend.
死亡时间你能确定吗
Are you sure about the time of death?
他摔倒的时候手表停了  10月27日4点
His watch broke when he fell. It says 4:00, october 27th.
如果凶手不是莫洛克  会是谁呢
Well, then if it wasn't Morlock, who was it?
他们又在找什么呢
And what were they looking for?
虽然不知道他们在找什么
Uh... I don't know what they were looking for,
但我知道受害者在藏什么
But I think I know what our vic was hiding.
那就是说乔纳斯·维斯特福尔  又名戴蒙
So Jonas Westfall, A.K.A. Daemon,
即将获得纽约大学
Was inches away from getting his master's
法医学硕士学位
In Forensic Science from N.Y.Y.
这看来都是他研究的一部分
This all looks like part of his research.
我小时候也曾热衷收集骨头
I went through a bone collecting phase When I was a kid.
你小时候肯定经历过什么
So whatever happened to you happened when you were young.
什么事  卡塞尔  你看到过谋杀吗
What was it, Castle? Did you witness a murder?
还是膝盖擦破流了血
Or did you skin your knee and it bled?
说到精神创伤
Hmm. Speaking of trauma,
不知道阿丽克西斯会在派对玩到多晚
I wonder how late Alexis is gonna be at her party.
可怜的费吉恩  正遭受着离别的痛苦
Poor Feggin is suffering from separation issues.
拜托  卡塞尔  我的情况你全知道  礼尚往来
Come on, Castle.You know mine. Tit for tat.
我收了你的礼
Just because I've seen your tat
不代表非得还礼
Doesn't mean I'm gonna show you my...
看看这个  两年前
Check this out. Uh, dated two years ago--
周日深夜  在利哈伊河上游的宾州森林
"A murdered woman was unearthed in the pennsylvania woods
发现一名女子被害  调查表明
"Above Lehigh river late sunday night. "Investigators say
-该女子埋在浅墓好几年了  -还有吗
- She'd been buried in the shallow grave for years."  -And?
根据遗体残骸  调查人员已经成功
"Based on the remains, investigators have attempted
将被害女子的脸部进行了法医学复原
A forensic reconstruction of the murdered woman's face."
那就是克鲁画中的女人
That's the woman from Crow's drawings.
然而在小说的插画中
Yet in the graphic novel,
她一直化身成死亡天使
She consistently appears as the Angel of Death.
好  既然克鲁着迷于戴蒙的案例研究
Okay, so Crow became obsessed with Daemon's case study.
为何要费尽周折藏起来呢
Why would they go to this much trouble to hide it?
为何有人为了找出来不惜杀人呢
Why would someone kill to find it?
-卡塞尔  -嗯
-Castle. -Hmm?
这些草图是四年前画的
These sketches were drawn four years ago.
不可能
No, no that's impossible.
尸体是两年前才发现的
This body wasn't discovered until two years ago.
除非克鲁能通灵  不然就是...
So either Crow is psychic or...
在该女子被害之前 他就认识她
Or he knew this woman before she died.
阿丽克西斯  你怎样  都还好吧
Hey, Alexis. How you doing? Everything okay?
不  老爸  是佩吉有事
No, dad. It's Paige.
我认为庞趣酒有问题  而且她喝太多了
I think the Punch is spiked, and she had too much to drink.
我怕她会出事
I'm afraid something's gonna happen to her.
马上到
I'm on my way.
上帝  她没事吧
Oh, my god. Is she all right?
我不知道  她不亲人家就得喝酒
I don't know. She was swapping drinks for kisses,
我想拉她走  可她不让
And I tried to pull her away, but she wouldn't let me.
给我杯水
Would you get me a glass of water?
-阿丽克西斯  别拉我  -佩吉
- Leave me alone, Alexis. - Paige.
你确信她没吐或失去意识吗
Now you're sure she hasn't been throwing up or unconscious?
-没  躺下吧  -好吧  打电话给她父母
- No, just falling down. - All right. Call her parents.
不要  我给...房租
Don't do it. oh, my 'rents... 'urder me.
请别这样  卡塞尔先生  就让我借宿一晚吧
Don' do it, Mr. Castle. Jus' let me sleep over.
-她在说什么  -醉话
- What is she saying? - It's just drunk talk.
她说不要打电话给她的父母   否则他们会杀了她的
She says don't call her parents or they'll murder her.
就让她借宿一晚  非得联络她父母吗
Just let her sleep over. Do we have to call her parents?
是的  给我号码
We do. Get me their number.
她会很麻烦的
She'll get in so much trouble.
总比你让她借宿强
Less than if you had left her there.
快点
Now.
-让她喝下去  -拜托
- Try to get her to drink that. - Please.
阿多拉  我们这样叫她的
Adora. That's what he called her.
我们在马修的作品中见过她很多年了
We've seen her in matthew's artwork for years.
-认识她吗  -不
- Do you know who she is?  - No
我们当她是虚构的人物
We just assumed that she was a figment of his imagination.
他说她是自己的灵魂
He called her his own personal ghost.
无论是他的梦境还是恶梦里都有她
He said she appeared in his dreams and nightmares.
她并非虚构  确有其人
Well, she's not a figment. She's very real.
你们确信不认识她
Are you sure you don't recognize her?
因为她可能是任何人
Because she could be anybody.
可能是一名老师  你的邻居
She could be a teacher, a neighbor.
肯定不认识  只在他作品中见过
No, I-I'm certain. We've only seen her in his art.
你知道  你儿子小时候是否受过
Do you know if your son experienced anything traumatic
-某种精神创伤  -你指什么
-When he was younger? -What do you mean?
我将马修的一些画
I showed some of Matthew's drawings
给一位临床医学家看过  他说看起来
To one of our therapists, and he said that it looked like
他可能目睹过一些烦心事
He might have witnessed something disturbing,
像什么暴力事件
Seen something very violent.
我确实想不起来有这种事
I-I really can't think of anything.
你有马修画这名女子的早期作品吗
Do you have any of Matthew's earlier drawings of this woman?
没有  他走的时候都带走了
No. He took it all with him when he left.
你可以去翻翻看他那个
Um, you might want to check the portfolio
装有巴克学院申请资料的包
With his application for Barker.
他心爱的作品都装在里面
All the work he cared about, he put in there.
谢谢  罗茜  我们会查的
Thank you, Rosie. We'll look into it.
怎么没见卡塞尔
What, no Castle?
他昨晚熬夜了  怎么了
Uh, no. he had a late night. What's up?
我跟宾州警署的人谈过了
I was talking to the Pennsylvania State Police
我们受害者的那位神秘女士  他们说
About our victim's mystery woman, and they said
我是两周内第二个打电话去问
I was the second person to call in the last two weeks
那名树林中发现的女人情况的
About the woman they found in the woods.
-谁还问过  -乔纳斯·维斯特福尔
- Did they tell you who else called?  - Jonas Westfall.
-戴蒙  -对  那个狼人
- Daemon.  - Yep, our werewolf.
他们的技术人员认定
And their forensics expert determined that
该女子18年前死于枪杀  胸部中弹
The woman died 18 years ago from a gunshot wound to the chest
凶器与杀死戴蒙的一样  也是9毫米手枪
From a 9-millimeter handgun, same as Daemon.
我就想  怎么回事  经过弹道对比
So I thought, what the hell? Compare the ballistics.
两颗子弹...完全吻合
The bullets... are a match.
两起谋杀相隔这么多年
Two murders that many years apart?
神秘女子还有什么线索吗
Anything on the mystery woman?
还是无法确定身份
Mnh-mnh. still haven't I.D.'ed her.
该女子被杀时
You know, Crow would've been 2 years old
克鲁应该才两岁
When that woman was killed.
你还记得两岁时发生的事吗
Do you remember anything from when you were that young?
-克鲁的公文包  -对
- Crow's portfolio? - Yeah.
有好东西给你看看
And there's something you gotta see.
眼熟吧
Look familiar?
同一棵树  跟找到尸体旁的那棵一样
It's the same tree, Just like where the body was found.
梦境不可能画得如此精确
You don't draw something with that precision from a dream.
那是他的记忆
He's remembering it.
克鲁亲眼目睹了那名女子被杀
Crow witnessed that woman's murder
当时他才2岁
When he was 2 years old.
应该和别人在一起
He had to have been with someone--
保姆  家人或者是凶手
A sitter or a family member or maybe even the killer.
调查一下弗雷曼家族的背景
Run a background check on the Freemans.
看看18年前他们住哪里
Find out where they were living 18 years ago.
没问题
You got it.
卡塞尔  阿丽克西斯还好吧
Hey, Castle. Alexis okay?
她...她是个很聪明的孩子
She's, uh... she's a smart kid.
你照看了费吉恩
You took care of Feggin.
对  伺候他不难
Yeah, well, he was... easy.
我把他放床上  他都没闹
He didn't even fuss when I put him to bed.
想知道更多这个离奇案件的消息吗
Yo. Ready for more tales of the weird and strangely odd?
我们调查了弗雷曼家族的过去
We looked into the Freeman family history.
弗雷曼是詹尼斯娘家的姓
Freeman is Janice's maiden name.
当她和艾伦结婚后  艾伦用了她的姓
When she and Alan got married, Alan took her name
马修也是
And so did Matthew.
要么他就是主张男女平等
Well, he's either a feminist
要么就是有所隐藏
Or he's hiding something.
-艾伦原来姓是什么  -麦金蒂
-  What's Alan's original last name?  -  Maginty.
我觉得他是在隐藏什么
And I think he was hiding something.
艾伦的前妻  伊丽莎白·麦金蒂
Alan's first wife, Elizabeth Mcginty,
18年前在新泽西的山峰市失踪了
Went missing from Summit, New Jersey, 18 years ago.
从此杳无音信
She was never found.
艾伦没说实话  他很清楚儿子在画谁
Alan lied to us. He knew exactly who his son was drawing.
画的就是亲生母亲
He was drawing his real mother.
从案发地点到山峰市只需几个小时
And Summit's only a couple of hours from where the body was found.
伊丽莎白·麦金蒂  原姓德莱顿  德莱顿
Elizabeth Mcginty, maiden name Dryden. Dryden?
-伊丽莎白·德莱顿  -怎么啦
-  Elizabeth dryden. -  What?
那个没有死亡日期的  还记得我说的
Question mark. Remember what I told you
那个墓碑的事吗
About gravestones telling stories?
克鲁是有目的而来的
Crow came here for a reason.
墓地管理人员说这家人
So cemetery management said that the family
为女儿举行了追悼会
Had a memorial service for their daughter
大约在她失踪五年后
About five years after she went missing.
戴蒙为了完成他的作品肯定看过无数张
Daemon must have looked at hundreds of
被重塑后的脸
Reconstructed faces researching his thesis.
很难想象  当他在克鲁的作品中认出
I can't imagine the shock when he recognized one
这个女人会有多么震惊
As the woman from Crow's drawings.
克鲁一定意识到
And Crow must have realized
多年来  家人一直让他蒙在鼓里
His family had been lying to him all these years.
她的坟上有鲜花
Huh. Fresh flowers on her grave.
克鲁把父亲带到了这里
Crow grabbed his father here
在母亲的坟前与他对质
To confront him with his mother's grave.
多年来  明知道儿子在画自己的母亲
All of these years, You knew your son was drawing his mother,
却对此绝口不提
And you never said anything.
我在保护我的家人
I was protecting my family
你在保护你自己
You were protecting yourself.
你这个冷血的凶手
You're a cold-blooded killer.
杀害妻子后谎报失踪
You killed your wife, and then reported her missing,
却不料被儿子在18年后发觉
And then 18 years later when your son found out,
于是再杀掉儿子
You killed him as well.
你不必作答
You don't have to respond to that.
不行  她指控我杀了自己的儿子
No, no, no, no. She's accusing me of killing my son.
我确实骗了马修  不过只想保护他
Yes, I lied to Matthew, but I did it to protect him.
他那时太小  理解不了
I thought he was too young to understand
-你当时有嫌疑  -肯定有嫌疑
-  You were a suspect  -  Of course I was a suspect.
我是她的丈夫
I was her husband.
可没有证据表明  我与她的失踪有关
There wasn't any evidence that tied me to her disappearance
我与此确实无关
'cause I had nothing to do with it.
詹尼斯和我的结合是一种转机
When Janice and I got married, it was like a chance...
开始新生活的转机
A chance at a fresh start.
得到了法律允许
And so as soon as you were legally able,
你就另结新欢
You married your Nanny.
那段暗淡的岁月中  詹尼斯一直陪在我们身边
Janice was there for us during a very dark time in our lives.
门口都是记者
We had press on the lawn.
好几天不得安歇
There were days without sleep.
我到处散发利兹[伊丽莎白的昵称]的寻人启事
I was handing out flyers with Lizzy's picture on it.
詹尼斯整理材料  还来照看马修
And Janice kept it together, and she protected Matthew.
那你为什么要对我们撒谎
Then why would you lie to us?
当时我女儿也在场
You told us in front of our daughter.
我能怎么办
What did you want me to do,
告诉她其实一切都是谎言
Tell her that everything she thought was a lie?
罗茜崇拜马修  才知道他的死讯
Rosie adored matthew. She had just found out he died.
-你会怎么做  -我会告诉她真相
-  What would you have done?  -  I would've told her the truth.
他第一次画他妈妈的时候才9岁
He was 9 years old when he first drew her face.
当他拿给我看时  我以为撞鬼了
He showed it to me. I thought I was seeing a ghost.
我想  孩子对母亲
I figured... she was still somewhere
仍然有些早期的记忆
In his head from his earlier memories.
可谎言说多也渐渐变成了事实
But we'd been living a lie for so long. It had become the truth
我怎么能告诉他  詹尼斯不是他的母亲
So how can I possibly tell him Janice wasn't his mather
他的生母已经过世呢
That his real mother ran away?
问完了吗  警探
Are we through here, detective?
休想用这样的理由蒙混过去
Not by a long shot, lawson.
康涅狄格州的警察
The Connecticut State police
在你家里发现了一把9毫米口径的手枪
Found a 9-millimeter handgun in your client's home,
我敢肯定  这把枪杀死了
And I am just betting that that is the same gun that killed
伊丽莎白·德莱顿·麦金蒂和乔纳斯·维斯特福尔
Elizabeth Dryden Mcginty and Jonas Westfall.
-不  我  -别再说了  艾伦
-  No, I  -  Don't say anything, Alan.
是吗  再看看这个
Oh, yeah. and there's also this.
你儿子目睹了他母亲被杀的过程
Your son witnessed his mother's murder.
不  那不可能
No. That's not possible.
这...这怎么可能
How... how is this possible?
拿一下  谢谢
Here. thank you.
劳驾
Excuse me.
你们打算让我们
Um, how much longer are you people gonna keep us waiting
在毫不知情的情况下  等上多久啊
Without letting us know what is going on?
我们正在努力调查  弗雷曼太太
We are trying to find the answers, Mrs. Freeman.
-斑点  -什么
-  Spots  -  what?
到处都是斑点  到处是血
"Spots all over. Blood all over.
我该把你藏起来  可怜的孩子
I should've buried you then, you wicked boy."
-你在说什么  -摩洛克的疯话
-  What are you talking about?  -  Morlock's crazy talk.
就像佩奇的酒后呓语  你得仔细体会
It's just like Paige's drunk talk. You have to translate it.
-摩洛克还关着吗  -关着呢
-  Is morlock still in holding?  -  Yeah.
弗雷曼太太  很抱歉耽误您这么久
Mrs. Freeman, I am so sorry this is taking so long.
但既然还要继续等
But as long as you have to wait,
你应该也想让自己更舒适一点
You might as well be comfortable.
看到自动贩卖机了吗
Have you seen our vending machines?
一直往前走  然后左拐
Uh, straight through here. Right. Just to the left here.
对了  就在那里  很好  一直往前
Perfect. Right in there. Excellent. Straight through.
噢  错了  转身
Oh, wrong. Turn--
啊  狠毒的贱人  你杀死了克鲁
aah! heartless bitch! Spots murdered the Crow!
凶手  凶手
Murderer! Murderer!
世界可真小啊
What a small world.
-拿好  -谢谢
-  Here you go  -  Thank you.
怎么回事
Why?
她杀死了伊丽莎白  从而得到你
She killed elizabeth so that she could have you to herself.
然后又杀了马修和他的朋友戴蒙
And then she murdered Matthew and his friend Daemon
那样你就永远不会知道了
So that you would never find out.
马修不知道该相信谁
Matthew didn't know who to trust,
于是让戴蒙帮他收藏证据
So he asked Daemon to hide the evidence,
却没料到她要精明得多
Which ended up being smarter than he ever realized.
她知道他们早晚会查出真相
She knew that it was only a matter of time
发现她的罪行
Before they figured out the truth about what she had done.
于是她跟踪戴蒙回家  打死了他
So she followed Daemon to his apartment and shot him.
那把枪也是杀死你前妻的凶器
She used the same gun that she used to kill your first wife.
那我儿子呢
What about my son?
他当时是要去墓地
He was on his way to the cemetery to, uh...
给他母亲献花
Lay down flowers at his mother's grave.
当她看到戴蒙家的木钉后
And when she saw the stakes in Daemon's apartment,
就想到把罪名推给
She figured that she could lay blame
那些在你儿子身边而不招你待见的人
On the people in your son's life that you already hated.
她把他养大
She raised him.
就像他的母亲一样
She was like his mother.
他让她经常想起她的罪行
He was a constant reminder of what she had done.
当他离开她时
And when he turned on her...
她就不再是他母亲了
She wasn't his mother anymore.
-爸爸  -宝贝
-  Daddy!  -  Oh, sweetie.
没事了
It's--it's okay.
会好的  没事了
It's gonna be fine. It's okay.
希望这事不会给她留下阴影
I hope this doesn't destroy her.
需要一段时间  然后某天  她会走出阴影
It will for a little while. And then one day, she'll wake up
将其变成生命中的小插曲
And it'll just be a part of her life.
谁知道呢  可能她会成为作家
Who knows? Maybe she'll become a writer
或者警察
Or a cop.
对了  你还没告诉我
You know, you still haven't told me
你为什么对谋杀着迷
Where your fascination with murder came from.
我5岁时  当时在海波汀避暑
I was five years old. We were summering in the Haptains.
我可以自由活动
I was pretty much left to my own devices
一天  我沿着沙滩走
This one day, I was walking along the beach.
走出几英里远
I was miles from where I had started.
正准备回去的时候
I was just about to turn back
看到什么东西被冲上岸来
When I saw something had washed up on the beach.
我以为是鲨鱼  海龟或海狮
I thought, maybe it's a-a whale Or a turtle or a sea lion.
我便跑过去看
So I ran over to see what it was.
是什么
What was it?
是个男孩  跟我一样大
It was a boy... my age.
是我们管家的儿子
It was our housekeeper's son.
肯定刚发生不久
It must have just happened...
因为海浪还没把血迹全冲干净
'cause the tide hadn't washed away the blood.
前一天  我们还一起玩捉迷藏
We had just played hide and seek the day before.
出什么事了
What happened to him?
一直没查出来
They never found out.
我很难过  卡塞尔
I'm so sorry, Castle.
-你杜撰的  -没错
-  You made that up?  -  It's what I do!
要知道  你演的很逼真
You know what? you are so getting it for that one.
晚会9点开始
The party is at 9:00.
我迫不及待想看看你穿什么来
I cannot wait to see what you're wearing.
你  你没装扮
Hey. you're... you're not in your costume.
我不下去了  没心情参加派对
I'm gonna stay upstairs. Not really in a party mood.
怎么了
What's wrong?
佩吉很生我的气
Paige was so angry with me,
她弄坏了我们的科学作品
She****our science project.
她修不好了
She could't figure it
她说是失手弄坏的
She said it was an accident
我不知道  她是不是故意报复我
But I don't know if she did it purposly to get back at me.
她那样做就太不对了
Oh, that is so wrong on so many levels.
付出那么多心血后  怎么又给毁了呢
How could she take care of him the way we did and then just destroy him?
不知道  我觉得那是...
I don't know. I think that's...
我写作的原因之一
That's one reason why I write about it.
有些人的行为让我无法理解
The way some people behave just... bewilders me.
但我要告诉你
I'll tell you this, though.
无论怎么样
There is nothing you could do that would stop me
我都会保护你或支持你
From protecting you or supporting you.
即使我的科学课得了良
Even if I get a "D" in science?
差也没关系
Even if you get an "F"
现在  赶快去换衣服
Now... go get changed.
妖魔鬼怪们马上就要来了
The goblinand ghouls Shall be arriving soon.
你身上有蜘蛛
You got a spider on you
小心点  那是我自调的饮料
Careful. that is a potion of my own concoction.
喝了之后不知道你会变成什么
Drink it, and who knows who or what you might become.
你可能会很好奇你的美臀会怎样
Also, you might wonder what happened to your pants.
听起来很合我胃口
H. Sounds like my kind of party.
这套19世纪的诗人行头花费不少吧
You throw a great shindig for a 19th-century poet, Mr. Poe.
我经常教导他
well, I've always told him,
宝贝  如果你想做什么事
"Darling, if you're gonna do something,
要么就轰轰烈烈  要么就别干
Do it big or don't do it at all."
-所以你挑了那顶帽子吗
-  Is that why you chose that hat?
卡塞尔  在找谁呢  贝克特吗
Hey, Castle. who are you lookin' for--Beckett?
没有  怎么了
No. why?
她说她不确定能不能来
She said she wasn't sure she'd make it.
她有些报告要写
She had some paperwork to finish up.
但现在还早呢
But it's still early.
诗人  找我吗
Hey, poe. Looking for me?
-你没装扮  -你很失望吗  卡塞尔
-  You're you.  -  You sound so disappointed, Castle.
我说了必须穿服装  就是要装扮一下
I said costumes mandatory. I mean, dress up.
恐怖一点
You know, be a little scary.
没错  但我要性感一点
Yeah, well, I was going for sexy.
老天啊
Jeez! ooh.
现在我们扯平了
Now we're even.
给你一只鸟
I'm giving you the bird.